okay most of you are probably hip
thrusting a lot like this you start out
right here you come up like
this
and some people can get a lot of glute
activation um this way in fact some of
my clients I still let do that way
because I'll palpate their glutes and
I'll feel and I can see had the GL
glutes are working well so I won't
correct it but I do have I have everyone
try this way and probably 80% of my
clients feel it better the way I'm about
to show you so here's what
characteristic of what a lot of people
are doing they come up to the top and
they're looking up and their chest is up
so they're kind of hyperextending their
spine and looking up at the top and I
tend to do this sometimes when I'm
trying to squeeze out one last rep or
when I go a little bit too heavy I'll go
and you'll see if I pause it at the top
you'll see my chest is up and I'm
looking up but here's what I want you to
do um so pick a spot on the wall that's
like what I'm doing right now is I'm
looking at where the wall meets the
ceiling at that crack so I'm going look
right
there
and I am going to keep my gaze there the
whole time and this is a tip from coach
Ben Bruno so I don't move from there and
you kind of watch my upper chest my head
my my neck all that happens is my neck
my my head and neck stay put while my
torso comes up so it looks like
this so what what's going on here is
that uh I have some I don't start off
with ribs down like this I don't start
here you want to start in some extension
so I have my chest up at the top so this
is a nice strong power ful position
however as I start raising the barbell
you'll see my you'll see this ribs Down
in action so what happens is as I start
coming up from here I end up doing this
so you'll see the distance from my rib
cuge to my pelvis actually shortens but
it doesn't do so through a crunching
action with the abdominals it does so
with the glutes so it may not look like
I'm achieving full hip extension here
but I actually am because I'm actually
getting a com com ation of hip extension
and posterior pelvic tilt and so say
you've got you know you've got the femur
inside the acetum you're getting hip
extension this way but you're getting
posterior public til this way so you're
getting a combination of both so you do
get full hip extension so let me show
you what this looks like with
weight the bar in
position okay chest up
just like that so at the top I've got
nice from
here this nice Flat Line instead of
being like
this so try it see which way you like
more and let me give you a little
anecdote um I went way down in weight
I've done 495 for 12 reps and I decided
to do 495 for three sets of three
focusing on getting the the hang of that
form and really feeling it I also
practice lowering it with my glutes so
using the glutes during the Ecentric
phase and being really
controlled and then I just added 20 lbs
and I did it twice a week for like three
and a half weeks and I ended up using I
think like 585 and 605 for three sets of
three so this was over like a 3 3 and
1/2 week period And I was taking a
shower and uh you know I was washing my
my rear and anyway I have feeling my
glutes and I was like whoa I've got some
new glute masks there so my glutes got
more muscular from doing this type of
form twice a week and working starting
out lighter and working way my way back
to my previous uh my previous strength
my previous 1 RM or my previous 3 RM
but now using better form so give it a
try and let me know what you think